MAREK CARTER

FULL STACK DEVELOPER







EDUCATION

BACHELORS
INFORMATION SCIENCE
University of South Florida
2013

FULL STACK MASTERY
Clever Programmer
2021

CLIENT-SIDE

HTML

CSS

JavaScript

ReactJS

Tailwind CSS

Styled Components

Next JS

React Native

Redux

SERVER-SIDE

Node JS

MongoDB

Firebase

Node Express

DEVELOPMENT & OPERATIONS

Figma

Scrum

Agile

GIT

JIRA

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Analytical Full Stack Developer with 1 year of experience developing projects and problem-solving. Skilled at developing software applications, full-stack web development, and collaborating with others. Looking to obtain a Full Stack Developer position to apply and develop the necessary skills for professional growth.

PROJECTS

UBER CLONE

Uber clone utilizing the latest technologies in React Native https://exp.host/@cartermarek/uber-clone

CSS, JavaScript, React Native, React Hooks, Google Places API, React Navigation, Redux, Tailwind CSS, React Native elements, React Native Maps

STARBUCKS CLONE

A simple Starbucks homepage during the holidays 2021, using pure JavaScript https://cartermarek.github.io/starbucks-clone/

HTML, CSS, JavaScript

TESLA CLONE

Tesla clone using advanced technologies like Redux and Styled Components https://mac-tesla-clone.herokuapp.com/

ReactJS, CSS, JavaScript, Redux, Styled Components

WORK EXPERIENCE

OVER THE ROAD TRUCK DRIVER

Max Carriers / Summit, IL / 2020 - Present

Overall, Max Carriers is a logistics transport company that deals mostly in the Northwest region. The main job is to deliver products and goods, on time, to a variety of customers. Successful and on-time deliveries, will create customer retention for future deliveries as well as improve the company's overall success with potential clients

- Handled a logbook daily that detailed the hours driven, rest periods, and miles driven electronically to stay compliant with DOT standards.
- Charted daily truck inspections by looking over to check for any abnormalities which have resulted in 0 breakdowns as a professional driver.
- Decreased gas consumption by properly planning trips and strategically having detours which have saved the company over \$100 per week.
- Collaborated with fleet manager and broker by keeping communication open and being thorough of any issues that occurred resulting in my work from the customer.

MAREK CARTER

FULL STACK DEVELOPER







SOFT SKILLS

Effective communication
Teamwork
Open-mindedness
Creativity
Problem-solving
Adaptability
Organization
Willingness to learn
Integrity
Dependability

INTERESTS

Critical thinking

Empathy

Playing Guitar
Coding
Video Games
Gym
Cooking

WORK EXPERIENCE

PROJECT CONTROLS ADVISOR FieldCore / Tampa, FL / 2017 - 2020

As a Project Controls Advisor, I oversaw multiple projects to make sure our company stayed within the proposed budget. I worked in tangent with the Project Manager for all projects and communicated daily to ensure project deadlines are met as well as any issues that may have occurred

- Produced weekly reports to management by collaborating with project managers and thoroughly reviewing the progress of projects to provide an up-to-date analysis of project finish time.
- Developed and maintained processes to control construction projects effectively and recommend improvement.
- Monitored project forecasted periodically and participated in monthly forecast reviews to highlight adverse schedule and cost variances for corrective actions.
- Steered the company to save over \$1000 by utilizing manpower and resources to get the job done efficiently and safely, which created work stability in order get requested to go to other job sites to help and save money.

HELP DESK TECHNICIAN

Granite / Tampa, FL / 2016 - 2017

Granite, which is now FieldCore, is part of General Electric. FieldCore is part of the energy sector which is very innovative in today's global market.

- Contributed to call center team productivity and customer satisfaction by serving as an escalation point for technical issues and resolved all issues promptly.
- Performed troubleshooting remotely or in person; this includes software upgrades, replacing hardware, updating software for bug fixes and preventive maintenance.
- Documented resolutions and analyzed trends for ways to prevent future issues.
- Was able to keep downtime for users down to a minimum of 1 hour for simple solutions, which increased customer satisfaction by 20%..